

Alex Maltsev

Q Long Beach, NY, 11561

+1(516) 490-7017 +7(903) 432-7501

Objective

Front-end Developer, Web Designer, UI/UX Designer.

Summary

An experienced Web Designer, Front-End Web Developer with an eye for design and attention to detail, with a grasp of HTML, CSS, Javascript including responsive design/development, I'm holding a package of skills: form web graphics to Javascript and Javascript frameworks. I can design and write code.



Technical Skills

- XHTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3
- Responsive Web Design
- CSS preprocessors, LESS, SASS
- Twitter Bootstrap, Zurb Foundation
- Ul/UX Design
- Adobe CS, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

- JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, jQuery Mobile
- JavaScript Frameworks, AngularJS, Backbone
- Hybrid Mobile Application Development
- PhoneGap, Ionic Framework
- CMS, Wordpress, PHP, SEO
- Git, Version Control Tools



Professional Experience

SuranceBay LLC

April 2015 - Present

Front-end Developer, Web Designer, UI/UX designer

Responsibilities include produce the UI/UX design wireframes, the graphic and html mockups, translation of the UI/UX design wireframes, mockups to actual code of websites and web apps. Bridge the gap between graphical design and technical implementation, taking an active role on both sides and defining how the application looks as well as how it works.

Farata Systems

January 2012 - Present

Front-end Developer, Web Designer, UI/UX designer

Produce the UI design wireframes, the graphic or html mockups, translation of them to actual code of various projects: websites and web apps. WordPress theme customization.

Intermix

May 2008 – June 2008

Web Designer, UI designer

Creating blog for Intermix (intermixonline.com) – unzippedintermix.com, currently blog.intermixonline.com - Wordpress, HTML, CSS, Javascript blog.intermixonline.com,

Various projects

September 2002 - Present

Front-End Developer, Web Designer, UI Developer, Mobile App Developer

Augast 2015 – September 2015 **Responsive corporate website** for the SuranceBay Agent Errors & Omissions (E&O) Insurance Program. <u>eno.surancebay.com</u>

August 2014 – March 2015 Insurance Portal (beta version).

Single Page Application. UI Developer. easy.insure

July 2015 **Responsive Wordpress-based website** for the Car Service Center "MC Garage" (Moscow, Russia) mcgarage.ru

January 2014 – May 2015 A member of the Front-end dev team on longterm **E-Commerce projects**. Modification, improving and enhancing the front-end of a Hybris based E-Commerce websites.

March 2015 Responsive one page website for taxi service "MC-Taxi" (Moscow, Russia) mc-taxi.ru

February 2013 Re-design Farata Systems IT consultancy blog - **Wordpress**, HTML, CSS, Javascript. flexblog.faratasystems.com

January 2012 – March 2012 Creating website for Farata Systems - **Wordpress**, HTML, CSS, Javascript faratasystems.com

June 2006, Moscow, Russia Personal website for Sergei Ryleev – Adobe Flash based front-end, Adobe Flash based admin. sergei-ryleev.ru

January 2002 - December 2004 Moscow, Russia B'n'B photo studio website <u>The Internet Archive – B'n'B photo</u> studio



Education

Southern Federal University (former Rostov State University)

(1991 - 1996) Master's Degree



Languages

English (Professional working proficiency) **Russian** (Native, bilingual proficiency)